Finding Aid for Sam Rabinovitz papers, 1940-1977
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Sam Rabinovitz papers 1940-1977
Rabinovitz, Sam.
2 linear feet
85357 Aa 2
Executive secretary, 1950-1969, of the Michigan Youth Commission. Correspondence, 1950-1971, and other papers relating to the work of the Michigan Youth Commission and its Youth Advisory Council, including reports and materials on state and national conferences; also photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Sam Rabinovitz (donor no. 6233 ) and came to the library in 1978.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Sam Rabinovitz served as executive secretary of the Michigan Youth Commission, a citizens' advisory organization on the problems of youth, from 1950 to 1969.
The Sam Rabinovitz papers consist of correspondence, 1950-1971, other papers and photographs relating to the work of the Michigan Youth Commission and its Youth Advisory Council, including reports and materials on state and national conferences. The collection is arranged into the following series: Biographical; Correspondence; Organizational; Conference materials; and Speeches and other Materials
Subjects:
Juvenile delinquency--Michigan.; Michigan Youth Commission.; Rabinovitz, Sam.; Youth--Michigan.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Michigan Youth Commission.; Rabinovitz, Sam.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Biographical
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - Undated 1951-1971, 17 folders (Box 1)
  - Correspondence with Margaret Price undated, 1950-1956 (Box 1)
- Organizational
  - American Red Cross Educational Advisory Committee 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Michigan Youth Guidance Program 1940-1945 (printed materials) (Box 1)
  - Michigan Youth Commission
    - Purpose, Organization. and History (Box 1)
    - Annual Reports 1952-1956, 1960-1968 (incomplete) (Box 1)
    - Program Description Statements 1969-1970 (Box 1)
    - Minutes
      - 1956 (Box 1)
      - 1969 (Box 1)
    - Reports
      - Undated (Box 1)
      - 1950, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - 1953-1954 (Box 1)
      - 1955-1957 (Box 1)
      - 1959 (Box 1)
      - 1960-1961 (Box 1)
      - 1964, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - 1965-1967 (Box 1)
      - 1968 (Box 1)
      - 1969 (Box 1)
    - 1960 White House Conference Follow-up Committee
      - Correspondence and reports
        - 1960 (Box 2)
        - 1961-1962 (Box 2)
      - Membership lists (Box 2)
    - Michigan Forum on Children and Youth October 18, 1963
      - Surveys of suggestions 1962 (Box 2)
      - Correspondence and reports
        - 1962 (Box 2)
        - 1963 (Box 2)
    - State Delinquency Project 1961-1963 (Box 2)
    - Detroit Delinquency Project 1962 (Box 2)
    - 1970 Michigan White House Conference Committee
      - 1968-1969 (Box 2)
      - 1970 (Box 2)
    - Testimony on Legislation 1960s (Box 2)
    - Newsletters 1969 (Box 2)
    - Membership lists (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Youth Advisory Council (to the Michigan Youth Commission)
    - General (Box 2)
    - Eighteen Year Old Vote (Box 2)
    - Preparation for Summer Employment Days May 6-8, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Smoking Survey 1969 (Box 2)
    - Newsletters (Box 2)
    - Articles about YAC (Box 2)
    - Thesis 1962 by Praim Sinanan Singh, entitled, "Characteristics and Participation of the Youth Advisory Council to the Michigan Youth Commission" (University of Michigan) (Box 2)
  - Thesis 1959 by Lauren Wondergem, entitled, "The Michigan Youth Advisory Council to the Michigan Youth Commission" (University of Michigan) (Box 2)
- Conference materials:
  - November 11-13, 1948 Governor's Conference on Children and Youth in Michigan (Box 2)
  - December 3-7, 1950 White House Conference on Children and Youth (Box 2)
  - February 26-27, 1954 Michigan Teen-age Driver Safety Conference (Box 2)
  - February 18-19, 1955 Michigan Teen-age Driver Safety Conference (Box 2)
  - February 9, 1961 Conference on Educational Opportunity (Box 2)
  - April 28, 1964 Governor's Conference on Youth (Box 2)
  - August 9-12, 1964 American Institute of Cooperation Annual Convention (Box 2)
  - October 23, 1964 Michigan Conference on Rural Youth (Box 2)
  - May 6-7, 1965 State-Wide Community Action Conference on Youth Opportunities (Box 2)
  - October 20-21, 1966 Midwest Regional Conference on Youth Employment (Box 2)
  - April 29, 1967 "Open-Ended" Youth Conference (Box 2)
  - October 12, 1967 State Recreation Conference on Vulnerable Children and Youth (Box 2)
- Speeches and other materials
  - Speeches
    - 1961-1962 (Box 2)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 2)
    - 1965-1968 (Box 2)
  - Governors' Remarks 1962-1969 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - University of Michigan Center for Continuing Education of Women Margaret Price-Lynn Bartlett Fellowship 1972-1977 (Box 2)
  - Photographs (Box 2)